

Curriculum Vitae for Sigmund Slang

Personal information

Address: Østbyveien 9C E-mail: sigmund@xal.no

0687 Oslo Phone: +47 99355541

Born: 30.03.94 Nationality: Norwegian

Summary

I am physicist from University of Oslo with a specialty on geophysical and seismological applications. During my thesis work I developed and applied convolutional neural networks to pre-stack seismic data for noise attenuation. I gained solid insight into machine learning tools such as Keras and Tensorflow as well as specialized tooling for seismology like SEGY-files and common seismic workflows. The skills I obtained form this work was further improved during my stay at Lundin Norway AS where I worked on similar projects enhancing and applying convolutional neural networks on post-stack seismic data. I have extensively used Python, making me highly proficient in this language, but I am also familiar with MATLAB, C++ and Bash.

Technical skills

Frameworks TensorFlow, Numpy, Keras, segylO, matplotlib, SciPy

Languages Python, Matlab, Bash, C++

Tools LaTeX, Linux, Git

Education

2019 M.Sc. in Geophysics and Seismology from the Faculty of Mathematics

and Natural Science, Department of Geosciences, University of Oslo. The title of my thesis was "Attenuation of Seismic Interference Noise using Convolutional Neural Networks" and was written in collaboration

with CGG.

2014 – 2017 B.Sc. in Geology and Geophysics from the Faculty of Mathematics

and Natural Science, Department of Geosciences, University of Oslo.

Professional experience

2020	Consultant at Expert Analytics AS
2019 - 2020	Consultant in Programming and Geophysics at Lundin Norway AS.
2019 – 2019	Summer intern at Inmeta, hired for specific project working with
	machine learning.
2015 – 2018	Annual summer job at Sommerskolen i Oslo teaching mathematics
	and programming to kids in age range 6-13 years old.

Languages

English Fluent

Norwegian Native speaker

Personal skills

Machine Learning	During my thesis work, as well as during my stay at Lundin Norway AS a key focus area revolved around developing and applying convolutional neural networks on seismic data for replication and enhancement of various seismic signal processes, such as de-noising and inversion. I have good experience with libraries such as TensorFlow and Keras.
Programming	Programming has been a key component throught my studies and
	has become a field of passion. Many courses featured a programming aspect, but programming was used in courses which did not as well.
Seismic Data	Studying Geophysics has given me a good insight in seismic data and seismic signal processing. I have also gained experience in industrial workflows during my stay at CGG during my thesis work and Lundin
	as a consultant.

Some interests and hobbies

Misc Gaming, Technology, Programming, Hiking